老大 我们进来了
Boss, we're in.
很好
Excellent.
货呢
And the goods?
成吨的高科技战利品
Tons of high-tech loot
如你所料 老大
just like you said, boss.
正如你所料
Just like you said.
当心
Look out!
永远的忍者神龟
恐怕这是真的 金凯
I'm afraid it's true, Kincaid.
我不是你的继弟
I'm not your stepbrother;
我是你同父异母的妹妹
I'm your half-sister.
我们中断当前节目
We interrupt this program
插播一条第六频道独家新闻
for a Channel 6 news exclusive.
今晚早些时候发生了一起大胆的抢劫案
There was a daring robbery earlier tonight
在市中心的一家高科技实验室
at a high-tech midtown laboratory.
附近的一个监控摄像头
A nearby surveillance camera
捕捉到了四个奇怪绿色生物的图像
captured this image of four bizarre green creatures.
李奥纳多
Leonardo!
米开朗基罗
Michelangelo!
多纳泰罗
Donatello!
拉斐尔
Raphael!
什么事?
You rang?
你们今晚好像失误了 孩子们
I fear you have been careless tonight, my sons.
我们存在的秘密暴露了
The secret of our existence has been compromised.
什么 今晚?
What, tonight?
我一直没出去
I haven't been out.
麦琪
Mikey?
我没有
Negatory.
斯普林特师父
Master Splinter.
我们整晚都和你待在一起
We've been cooped up in here with you all night.
那你们怎么解释...这个
Then how in the world do you explain... this?
四只生物的图像有点模糊
The image of the four creatures is a bit grainy
即便如此 还是能看出来
but even so, you can make out
好像是四只大乌龟的样子
what appear to be four large Turtles.
啊?
Wha...?
这...
It's...
这肯定是个恶作剧 对吧
it's got to be some kind of gag, right?
你看我在笑吗 拉斐尔
I am not laughing, Raphael.
来看看其他新闻 曼哈顿持续发现
In other news unusual underground seismic activity
不同寻常的地震活动
continues to be reported throughout Manhattan.
这里
Here.
我找到那张照片了
I've got the image.
他们确实长得像我们
They do look like us.
无论"他们"是谁
Whoever "they" are.
他们在跟什么人打
Who are they fighting?
紫龙帮
The Purple Dragons!
这么说 这些乌龟把戏是韩搞的鬼
So Hun's behind all this turtle-y fun?
你们看到这个了吗
Are you guys seeing this?
新闻上到处都是
It's all over the news.
我们看到了 艾普尔
We see it, April.
我们正要去查个水落石出
And we're about to get to the bottom of it.
这次收获满满 老大
It was a sweet score, boss.
我们抢到了各种各样的高科技产品
We grabbed all kinds of high-tech goodies.
但真正的大奖在这里
But the real prize is right in here.
我们抓到他们了 老大
We got 'em, boss
终于抓到他们了
we finally got 'em.
来看看...
Say hello...
忍者神龟们吧
to the Ninja Turtles.
嗯?
En?
难道你想见的不是我们
You were expecting maybe somebody else?
嗯...我不知道这些怪胎是谁
Em... I don't know who these freaks are
但他们不是那些忍者神龟
but they're not the Turtles.
大块头 如果我们不是忍者神龟
Chumley, if we're not the Turtles
那还有谁能是
I don't know who is.
说得好 拉斐尔
Good one, Raphael!
我们在他们身上找到这个
We, found this on them.
忍者的东西
Ninja type stuff.
对吧 老大
Right, boss?
嘿
Hey.
你不是应该给我们个打电话的机会吗
Don't you owe us one phone call?
我非常清楚要打给谁
Like, I totally know who I'm calling.
披萨外卖
Pizza delivery!
这是什么
What is this?
这是变异液
That's just ooze.
我们经常为了这个和水桶头打起来
We fight old bucket-breath over that stuff all the time!
水桶头?
"Old bucket-breath"?
你知道的 平底锅脸
You know-- old frying-pan face.
铁圆顶 铁嘴
Chrome dome? Metal mouth?
铁牙怪
Tin teeth.
你们这些怪胎在说什么
What are you freaks talking about?
这家伙脑子有点铁
A mind like a steel trap, this one.
你懂我意思吗
Know what I'm saying?
喂 我们在说施莱德
Hello? We're talking about Shredder.
这和施莱德有什么关系
What does this have to do with the Shredder?
就像米开朗基罗说的
Like Michelangelo said
这是基因诱变剂 我们一直在防止
it's just some mutagen we stopped Shred-head
它们落到施莱德手里
from getting his claws on.
诱变剂
Mutagen?
我劝你小心点
I'd be careful with that if I were you.
怎么回事
What the...?
这个可能会派上用场
This could really come in handy...
如果施莱德真的回来了
especially if the Shredder is back.
我们怎么处理这些人 老大
What do you want us to do with these guys, boss?
我已经有四只乌龟要担心了
I've already got four Turtles to worry about.
这些是多余的
These are superfluous.
很高兴认识你们 多余的家伙
Nice knowing you, Superfluous.
什么
What the...?
啊
Aah!
快把它弄走
Get it off me!
希望你别介意
Hope you don't mind
我们自己进来了
but we let ourselves in.
实际上
Actually
看来我们好像已经在里面了
it kind of looks like we're already here.
嘿 那些家伙和我们长得一样
Hey, those dudes look just like us.
少抬举自己了
Don't flatter yourselves!
该我们上场了
That's our cue!
拉斐尔 当心
Raph! Look out!
谢了 兄弟
Thanks, bro!
让一让
Excuse me!
真棒
Sweet!
他们的腰带上写着首字母
They got little initials on their belt buckles!
就像超级英雄一样
Like superheroes!
哇哦
Whoa!
好诶
Yeah!
真有意思
Fascinatin'!
帮个忙好吗 麦琪
Little help here, Mikey?
收到
You got it!
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
冷静点 伙计
Cool off, dude!
哈哈 他叫你冷静点
Heh-heh! "Cool off," he says.
神龟力量
Turtle Power!
你怎么能不爱这些家伙呢
How can you not love these guys?
哇哦
Whoa!
这下真是满'墙'忠烈
Now, that was off the wall!
快走
Come on!
以后再联系
Let's stay in touch.
好了
All right,
该回答问题了
time for some answers.
你们到底是什么人
Who the shell are you guys?
我正想问你们呢
I was about to ask you the same question.
别装可爱
Don't get cute.
没办法 我们天生就这样
We can't help it-- we were born that way.
听着 我们冒着生命危险
Look, we just risked our shells
把你们从韩和紫龙帮手里救出来
rescuing you from Hun and the Purple Dragons.
我认为我们有权得到一些答案
So I think we're entitled to some answers.
他说的对
He's right.
这是他们应得的
They've earned it.
一点儿没错
Absolutely.
所以 快说呀
So... spill!
必须的
You bet.
但是要先吃午饭
Right after lunch!
什么
What?
不
No!
他们在干嘛呢
What are they doing?
我受够了 他们完蛋了
That's it-- they're toast!
我们不能在光天化日之下到处跑
We can't go running around in broad daylight!
他们可不管这些
Doesn't seem to be stopping them.
你好 最近怎么样
Hey there! How's it going?
你好 嗨
Hello. Hi.
万一他们被不该看见的人看见了
If they get spotted by the wrong...
走吧 是时候呼叫增援了
Come on, time to call in reinforcements.
我都快饿死了
I'm starving.
我现在能吃掉一整块派
I could eat a whole pie myself!
中奖了
Score!
不用排队
No line!
我们要四个大披萨
We'll take four large pizzas
配德国泡菜 金枪鱼 椒盐卷饼和彩虹软糖
with sauerkraut, tuna fish, pretzels and jelly beans.
也许他们的彩虹软糖卖完了
Maybe they're out of jelly beans?
啊偶 警察来了
The boys in blue!
我们从后门溜出去吧
Let's slip out the back!
哇哦 嘿 放开我们
Whoa! Hey! Let us out of here!
怎么回事 放开我
What's going on? Let us go!
嘿 这是怎么回事
Hey! What's the big idea!
你们惹错人...
You totally picked the wrong...
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter?
你们认识我?
You know me?
嗯 没错 但是
Well, yeah, but...
您换了个发型吗
Did you get a perm job or something?
你看起来 不太一样了
You look, different.
回想起来
Come to think of it
最近一切都不太一样
everything's been looking a little different lately.
没错 自从那次大爆炸之后
Yeah. Ever since that big explosion
纽约就一直不太一样了
New York just hasn't been the same.
爆炸?
Explosion?
是啊 在我们和施莱德的战斗中
Yeah, during our, battle with Shredder.
施莱德?
The Shredder?
也许你们应该从头说起
Perhaps it would be best if you started from the beginning.
好吧
Well...
我们正在施莱德的终极武器里大战
we were mixing it up inside the Shredder's ultimate weapon
在它的电子圆宫里
the Technodrome
试图阻止他拿到诱变剂
trying to keep him from getting his claws on some vials of mutagen.
我们正在想办法彻底结束战斗
We were looking for a way to end the fight once and for all
这时多尼想到了一个好主意
when Don had a rockin' idea--
使用电子圆宫自带的维度传送门
use the Technodrome's own transdimensional portal
把它传送回原来的地方
to send it back from whence it came.
多尼开始施展他的科技
Don started working his techno-magic
但是
but...
接下来我们所知道的就是
The next thing we knew,
我们回到了城里
we were back in the city.
然后我们又干起老本行
And we got back to doing what we do best,
打击罪犯
taking down scuzz-buckets.
韩和紫龙帮
Hun and the Purple Dragons.
也许我们已经不在堪萨斯了
But maybe we're not in Kansas anymore.
至少不是我们的堪萨斯
Not our Kansas, anyway.
伙计 你是说...
Dude, are you saying...
我是说 电子圆宫的维度传送门
I'm saying the Technodrome's transdimensional portal
可能把我们传送到了另一个世界
might have zapped us all to a different world.
你们的这个施莱德 他也在这里吗
This Shredder of yours, he's here, too?
我们的目标已经明确了
Our path is clear.
我们必须齐心协力找到这个电子圆宫
Together we must find this Technodrome.
这可能是送他们四个回家的唯一办法
It may be the only way to get these four home.
搓头大法
Noogie!
别闹了 伙计们
Cut it out, you guys.
越快越好
The sooner the better.
主引擎已离线
Primary engines off-line.
该死的机器
Blasted machine!
只是一场小小的战斗
How does a minor battle with those
怎么就让引擎...
annoying Turtles cause the engines to...?
什么鬼东西
What the devil?
时间反常现象
A temporal anomaly?
看来是维度传送门
It seems the transdimensional portal
把电子圆宫传送到了另一个时空
has thrown the Technodrome into an entirely different dimension.
我讨厌那些乌龟
I hate those Turtles.
又怎么了
What now?
边界被闯入
Perimeter breach.
你是对的 多纳泰罗
You were right, Donatello.
追踪近期奇怪的地震活动
Tracking the recent weird seismic activity
确实直接把我们带到了...
has led us straight to the...
电子圆宫
Technodrome!
一个带轮子的巨型高尔夫球?
A giant golf ball on wheels?
这就是你们的施莱德的终极武器?
That's your Shredder's ultimate weapon?
八只乌龟?
Eight Turtles?
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know how this came to be
但很快就会一只都不剩了
but soon there will be none.
消灭他们 全部消灭
Destroy them, all of them.
我很乐意 施莱德主人
With great pleasure, Master Shredder.
比波和洛克史迪
BeBop and Rocksteady?
说出你们的遗言吧 乌龟们
Say your prayers, Turtles.
你们平时是怎么处理这些情况的
So how do you guys normally handle these situations?
神龟力量
Turtle power!
呜呼 来吧
Whoo-hoo! All right!
你怎么能不爱上这些家伙?
Don't you just love these guys?
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
卡哇邦嘎 呜呼
Cowabunga! Whoo-hoo!
天哪 现在就像有五个麦琪一样
Geez, it's like having five Mikeys now.
机器人
Robots?
爆炸机器人
Exploding robots.
准备受死吧
Prepare to get plasmarized.
我看未必
I don't think so.
我要碾碎这些龟壳
I'm gonna pulverize you shellbags.
来吧
Sure.
只能等你获得假释了
Just as soon as you get out on parole.
别逗乐了 伙计们
Cut it out, guys.
这儿还在打架呢
I'm trying to fight here.
来啊 谁想尝尝
Yeah, who wants some?
全垒打!
Stee-rike!
我想给你一记全垒打
I'll give you a strike!
哇 真是个暴脾气
Wow, what a hard case.
兄弟 我经历过太多
Bro, I could tell you stories.
该死的乌龟
Blasted Turtles!
施莱德 你这个笨手笨脚的白痴
Shredder, you bungling idiot.
我正忙着呢 克朗
I'm in the middle of something here, Krang.
你先是把我们困在这个地狱维度里
First you get us stuck in this infernal dimension
现在又在费力攻打这些原始生物
and now you struggle...to defeat these primitive creatures.
如果我的X维度的部队在这里
If my troops from Dimension X were here...
少在这儿碎碎念你的X维度了
Quit nagging about Dimension X.
这个维度的麻烦已经够多了
We're having enough trouble in this dimension.
你没看到现在有八只乌龟吗
Can't you see there are eight Turtles now?
等等
Wait.
对了 当然了
That's it. Of course.
如果这个维度有自己版本的乌龟
If this dimension has its own version of the Turtles
也许它也有自己的施莱德
perhaps it has its own Shredder as well.
哦 也许还会有它自己的克朗
Ooh, and maybe even its own Krang.
那可就太好了
Why, that would be wond...
紧急电源现已启用
Emergency power now online.
太棒了
Excellent.
现在 让我们争取一点时间
Now, let's buy ourselves a little time.
搞什么把戏
What gibes?
等等我们
Wait for us!
等等 老大
Hold up, boss!
快点 他们要跑了
Come on, they're making a run for it!
在这个维度上 没找到什么克朗
Nothing comes up for Krang in this dimension.
什么
What?
施莱德的话...
Shredder, on the other hand...
出现了
there he is
而且他非常厉害
and he is magnificent.
多么强大 多么有力
What strength, what power.
我多么渴望有这样一个盟友
How I've longed for an ally such as this
不像某些淌着鼻涕的白痴
so unlike the sniveling idiots
我已经忍受了很久了
that I've been forced to suffer.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
我能听到你说话
I can hear you!
现在 去找他
Now, to find him.
真奇怪
Strange.
他不在地球
He's off-world.
没关系
No matter.
我可以设置传送器
I will program the matter transporter
把他直接传送到这里
to beam him to us directly.
这是一个转折点 克朗
This is a turning point, Krang.
世界将会颤抖在我们的强强联合之下
The world will tremble before the combined power
强大的施莱德和他的...
of mighty Shredder and his...
啊?
Ah?
粉色鼻涕虫
Pink slug?
噢...我想要一个超级邪恶的盟友
Aw...I wanted a super sinister ally.
说不好 我看着挺不错的
I don't know, he looks all right to me.
那个弱小的生物难道
Could that puny creature
真的是这个维度的施莱德?
actually be this dimension's Shredder?
安静
Quiet.
开始解冻再生
Commencing cryoregeneration.
不
No.
傻瓜 你把他烧焦了 是不是
Fool, you overcooked him, didn't you?
我的每个步骤都是完全正确的
I did everything exactly right.
应该起作用的
It should have worked.
它应该活过来了
It should be alive.
你搞砸了
You botched it.
你搞砸了!
You botched it!
别忘了你在跟谁说话
You forget who you talk to
你这个哭鼻子的臭虫
you whimpering worm!
啊
Aah!
我是施莱德
I am the Shredder!
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
放手
Let go.
这些人是什么蠢货
What fools are these
真是活腻了...
so weary of life...
什么…
Wha...?
竟敢滥用施莱德的名字
...that they take the name of the Shredder...
我的名字
...my name in vain?
好炫的车子
Nice wheels!
非常狂野
Totally radical!
请告诉我咱们不是在兜圈子 多尼
Please tell me we're not just driving in circles, Donnie.
我调整了装甲车的跟踪装置
I recalibrated the hauler's tracking apparatus
让它追踪具有电子圆宫外形的地下物体
to seek an underground object similar to the Technodrome surface area.
你看
See?
地下声纳
Subterranean sonar.
真是好主意 多纳泰罗
Brilliant notion, Donatello
书呆子
Nerds.
天龙五号呼叫龙王
Sky Dragon Five to Dragon King.
看到他们了 老大
I see them, boss.
正在莱丁顿街往南走
We going south on Lectington.
好的
Good.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
这是我们的引擎室
And this is our engine room
不幸的是 目前正在维修中
currently under repair unfortunately.
请原谅 最尊贵的客人
Please excuse me, most honored guest.
克朗 怎么花了这么长时间
Krang, what's taking so long?
我没法一直哄着这个外星人开心
I can't keep this alien entertained forever.
你早该提前修理的
You should have done of that...
在你把它传过来之前
before you marauder him here.
都是你的错
this is all your fault.
我的错? 你在说什么
my fault? what you talking about?
我要看到你说的维度传送装置
I wish to see the transdimensional portal device you spoke of.
现在
Now.
请稍等 先生
A moment, sir.
克朗
crane.
一切都准备好了
All is ready...
强大的施莱德
...Mighty Shredder.
就等你下令了
Just give the word.
现在就执行 该死的的鼻涕虫
The word, you smug slug, is given.
你
You...
小家伙 你是在自掘坟墓
Little man, you have made a grave...
坟墓...
a grave...
坟...墓...
...a grave...
我还以为他能帮我们打败乌龟
I thought he could help us defeat the Turtles
但他...他疯了
but he-he's insane.
说不定能学到点有用的东西
Perhaps we may still learn something useful di...
如果解剖了它
...dissecting it?
入侵者警报
Intruder alert.
不会又是那些该死的乌龟吧
Not those blasted turtles again!
我叫卡拉
I am called Karai.
我是他的女儿
I am his daughter.
看不出一点家族的相似之处
Not much of a family resemblance.
你也想像他一样多嘴吗
Will you be a nuisance as well?
不会的 迷人的女士
Never, charming lady!
我费了很大的力气追踪父亲的信号
I have gone to great lengths to keep vigil over my father.
但是今天 他从监控系统中消失了
But today he vanished from my monitoring systems.
当我重新定位到他
When I was able to relocate him...
竟然出现在这里
...he was here.
这是怎么回事
How is this so?
是...是...物质传送器
The m-m-matter transporter,
我们把他传送过来的
we beamed him here.
这项技术现在属于鬼脚帮了
This technology is now property of the foot.
有了它 我将重铸父亲的荣耀
With it, I will restore my father,
唯一正宗施莱德
the one true Shredder to glory!
唯一正宗?
One true?
你给我等...
Now wait just...
你又把咱搅进了什么浑水
Another fine mess you've gotten us into.
闭嘴吧你
oh, shut up.
上面显示
According to this
电子圆宫已经不远了
the Technodrome's close.
干得好 孩子们
Wel done, my sons.
大家还好吗
Everyone all right?
什么情况
What the shell?
带亲戚进城怎么不告诉我们一声
You didn't tell us you had family in town.
你也没告诉我
And you didn't tell me
你们的双胞兄弟带着超强诱变剂
your doubgangers were carrying super-powered mutagen.
他在说什么
What's he talking about?
那东西只洒了一点点在我手下身上
That stuff barely splattered my man here.
想象一下 如果再多一点能做到什么
Imagine what I could do with more.
把瓶子给我 你这个小怪胎
Give me those vials, you little freak.
再见
See ya.
嘿 大怪物
Hey! gruesome!
鲸鱼喷水 老兄
Like, there she blows dude.
笑死我了
I cracked me up.
坏狗狗 蹲下 快蹲下
Bad dogy! Down! Down, boy!
让一让 借过
Gangway! coming through!
把诱变剂给我
Give me that mutagen.
想得美
I don't think so.
李奥
Leo!
不
No!
炮弹来了
Incoming!
父亲 你没事吧
Father! Are you all right?
我...没事
I... believe so.
"父亲"
"Father"?
我们得把你送回老巢
We need to get you back to the lair.
兄弟们 下水道时间到了
Time to hit the sewers, my brothers!
好的
Yeah! All right!
你们维度的井盖重多了
These things are a lot heavier in your dimension.
别挡道 胖子
Out of the way, tubby!
好了 大家都到池子里去
All right, everybody into the pool.
噗 你们的下水道真臭
P.U.! Your sewers really stink!
嗯 你们又没有鼻孔
Um, you don't have any nostrils.
被你说中了
Touché.
呀
Yeah!
嘿 电子圆宫怎么办
Hey. What about the Technodrome?
那个大货箱的速度还没你们快
That crate moves about as fast as you guys.
我们会追上的
We'll catch up to it.
嘿
Hey!
哈 我的了
Ha! Mine!
韩又赢了
Hun wins again!
嗯 你可能得看仔细点 赢家先生
Um, you might want to take a closer look, Mr. Winner.
把这脏东西拿开
Get this crud off!
还是不要保持联系了
Let's not stay in touch.
不
No...!
把它从我身上拿开
Get it off me!
快拿开
Get it off me...!
韩
Hun...
我的老朋友
my old friend.
你
You!
今天过得不顺吗
Having a bad day?
看看他们对我做了什么
Look what they've done to me!
该死的的乌龟
Accursed Turtles!
也许我们又一次有了共同的目标
Perhaps we have common cause once again, you and I.
好吗
Yes?
好的...主人
Yes... master.
我不明白
I don't understand it.
追踪系统正在逼近
The tracking system was closing in
然后突然
and then suddenly
噗的一下 没信号了
poof!-- static.
就像电子圆宫消失了一样
It's like the Technodrome disappeared.
谁知道我们接下来该做什么
Any idea what we should do next?
我! 我! 我知道! 我知道!
Me! Me! I know! I know!
除了出去吃一顿披萨以外
Other than going out for a slice?
我早就说过 没办法和这些呆瓜一起头脑风暴
I told you, you can't brainstorm with these goofballs.
他们根本没有头脑
They ain't got no brains!
嘿 我们同意你的说法
Hey! We resemble that remark.
说得好 伙计
Good one, dude!
我的个维度X啊 你们到底在干什么
What's in the name of Dimension x do you think you're doing?
那个控制台花了我很多钱的
I paid a fortune for that console.
还有你 都弄得掉漆了
and you're ruining the paint job.
别再抱怨了 克朗
Silence your incessant whining, crane.
我的分身只不过是在
My counterpart is simply
给这地方做点恰当的改装
giving this tub a much needed refit.
在我看来 他的做法十分慷慨
Very generous of him if you ask me.
显然是在报答我救了他
No doubt he wishes to repay me for rescuing him.
我的座位
My command chair.
醒醒吧 笨蛋 我们有了新老大
Face it, fool. We're under new management.
装修得怎么样了 卡拉
How go the repairs, Karai?
很好 父亲
Very well, Father.
X维度的技术非常荒谬
The technology of Dimension X is ridiculous
但是经过乌特罗姆科技改进之后
but once revised with Utrom science
将会有巨大的威力
it will prove devastating.
是的 两者融合得很好
Yes, the two merge well together.
这具新身体就是证明
This new body is proof of that.
还有更多证据
And more proof
他们的机器步兵
their robotic Foot Soldiers.
笨拙 软弱
Clumsy, weak,
几乎...如同卡通
almost......cartoonish.
但现在
But now...
经过适当修改后
with the proper modifications--...
十分致命
...lethal!
我们的人力部队也得到了升级
Our human troops have also been upgraded.
通过分析感染了韩的诱变剂
By analyzing the mutagen that infected Hun,
我们成功设计出了自己的变种人军队
we have successfully engineered our own mutant army!
很快我就会让这个世界屈服
Soon I will bring this world to its knees!
然后
And then...
等等 站住!
Wait! Stop!
把我的指挥椅搬回来
Come back here with my command chair!
这是命令
That's an order!
之后 也许轮到我那废物分身的世界
And then, perhaps, the world of my worthless counterpart.
无限的可能性已经向我敞开
Infinite possibilities have been opened to me
多亏了这个电子圆宫
thanks to this Technodrome.
我将统治多元宇宙 卡拉
I shall rule the multiverse, Karai.
电脑
Computer...
这是施莱德
This is the Shredder.
身份确认 已识别施莱德
Identity confirmed. recognize Shredder.
迟瑞尔 小禄崎 阿库拉公爵 毁灭者
Ch'rell. Oroku Saki. Duke Acureds. Destroyer of...
电脑
computer,
我对这个"传送门"的潜力很感兴趣
i am most intrigued of the implication of this... portal.
我想知道其它维度的知识
I wish to learn about alternate dimensions.
告诉我..所有的一切
Show me... everything!
拜托 拉斐尔 高兴点
Come on, raph, lighting up.
我们的卡哇邦嘎表亲没那么坏 对吧 伙计们
our Cowabunga cousins aren't so bad, right, guys?
戳耳朵
Wet willy!
你们抓到我了
you got me.
不错? 他们就是来搞笑的
not bad? They are clown.
根本不是忍者
Not ninjas.
什么?
Yeah?
没错
yeah.
够了 别吵架了
Enough, stop this, bickering.
这正是敌人想让你们做的
You only do your enemy's work for him.
你们是忍者
You are Ninja.
你们全都是
All of you.
这里欢迎你们所有人
And all are welcome here.
别让你的老师难堪
Do not embarrass your Sensei.
他也许长得不像我们的斯普林特
He may not look exactly like our Splinter,
但说起话来很像他
but he sure sounds like him.
那个...
Yeah.
抱歉刚才那样说你们
Sorry about the clown crack.
听着 伙计们
Listen, guys,
我们已经对付过施莱德
we've tangled with Shred-head
和他的电子圆宫很多次了
and his Technodrome plenty of times.
事实上 在我们家里就有各种
In fact, we got all kinds of special
反电子圆宫的装备
anti-Technodrome gear back home
专门为这样的情况准备的
for just such an occasion.
特制的反电子圆宫装备
Special anti-Technodrome gear?
当然 但是正如李奥纳多所说
Certainly, but like Leonardo said
它们都在我们维度的家里
it's back in our home dimension.
我们需要造一个维度传送杆之类的东西才行
We'll need to build some kind of transdimensional portal stick to get there
一个通往其他维度的大门
a gateway into other dimensions
而且足够小 可以装进大部分行李舱
but small enough to fit into most overhead compartments.
唐尼 他说的这个东西
Donni, whatever he's talking about
能做出来吗
can it be done?
我们见过时间旅行窗口 赛博空间传送器
We've seen time-travel windows, cybermat transporters--
但是一根棍子里的维度传送门?
but a dimensional portal in a stick?
听起来..挺傻的
It sounds... well, silly.
无意冒犯
No offense.
来吧 巫师先生
Come on, Mr. Wizard.
这会很容易的
It'll be easy.
不是只有你一个人
You're not the only one who needs to use
需要用维度传送门 你知道吗
the transdimensional portal you know.
开门
Open up!
你在里面干嘛呢
What are you doing in there anyway?
我的身体
My body!
傲慢的鼻涕虫
Insolent slug.
施莱德要做什么是他自己的事
The Shredder's business is his and his alone.
你再别想去打扰他
Do not seek to interrupt him again.
父亲 怎么了
Father, what is it?
发生什么了
What's wrong?
你在里面看到了什么
What did you see in there?
乌龟 卡拉
Turtles, Karai.
忍者神龟
Ninja Turtles.
我需要获得他们 两个队伍都要
I must have them-- both teams.
立刻就要
At once.
是的 复仇时刻终于来了
Yes, revenge at last!
我就知道你会挺过来的
I knew you'd come through.
我们可以一起摧毁乌龟
Together we can crush the Turt...
韩
Hun!
今晚你要去狩猎
Tonight you hunt.
找到对你做了这一切的人 把他们带给我
Find those who did this to you and bring them to me.
我会做到的 主人
It will be done, Master.
好的 退后
Okay, stand back.
应该管用的呀
That should have worked.
应该管用? 这玩意不可能管用
Should have worked? That'll never work.
这根本不是一个维度传送杆
That's not a transdimensional portal stick.
这就是一个...手电筒
That's... a flashlight.
它曾经是一个手电筒
It was a flashlight.
但只需稍微重新布线
But with a little rewiring
再加上许多乐观的想法
and a lot more positive thinking
它很快就会成为一根维度传送杆
it'll soon be a transdimensional portal stick.
现在把锤子递给我
Now hand me that hammer.
这是一把扳手
This is a wrench.
无关紧要
Details.
科学不一定全靠事实 你知道吗
Science isn't all about facts, you know.
什么情况
What the shell?
乌龟们
Turtles!
不
No!
他们怎么找到我们的
How'd they find us?
他们跟着鼻子走
They followed their nose.
鼻子知道
The nose knows.
是谁敢来扰乱我们家的宁静
Who disturbs the sanctity of my home?
认不出我了吗 啮齿动物
Don't you recognize me, rodent?
韩
Hun?
来看看你儿子们的杰作吧
Come examine your son's handiwork.
已经到中午了吗
Is it noon already?
机器人2.0
Robots 2.0?
你的新造型是怎么回事 大怪物
So what's with the new look, Gruesome?
诱变剂把我变成了我最后碰过的东西
That mutagen turned me into the last thing I touched.
肮脏的变种乌龟
Mutant Turtle filth!
他说的不对
It's not true.
我们定期洗澡的
We shower regularly.
你来这里干什么 韩
Why are you here, Hun?
你想要什么
What do you want?
你们还真是一无所知
You have no idea what this is about, do you?
你们甚至不知道他回来了
You don't even know he's back.
他?
He?
真正的施莱德
The one true Shredder.
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter!
刚刚发生了什么
What just happened?
斯普林特老师在哪里
Where's Master Splinter?
我们在哪里
Where are we?
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
伙计们
Dudes!
好唉
Yeah! All right!
我们到家了
We're home!
什么
What?
这就是你们的维度?
This is your dimension?
为什么看起来这么...
Why does it all look so...?
奇怪
...weird?
没错 哪里都比不上家里
Yup. There's no place like home!
我们到底来这里做什么
What the shell are we doing here?
我们得回去
We got to go back!
不知道斯普林特老师遇到了什么麻烦
Master Splinter's in who-knows-what kind of trouble.
多纳泰罗赶在屋顶把我们压扁之前
Donatello ported us out
把我们传送出来了
just before your roof flattened us into pizza pies.
我就说会管用的
Told you it'd work.
我们要回去
We're going back.
我们要救出斯普林特
We'll save Splinter
还要阻止那个电子圆宫
and we're stopping that Technodrome.
但是还有一个问题
But we've got another problem.
韩提到真正的施莱德
Hun mentioned the one true Shredder.
你们知道这意味着什么
And you know what that means.
我们的小外星人乌特罗姆回来了
Our little alien Utrom is back.
乌特罗姆·施莱德
Utrom Shredder?
听起来像瑞典人
Sounds Swedish.
停下 停下 快停下
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
你们几个就不能严肃一点吗
Can't you guys be serious about anything?
他们是对的
They're right.
这件事很严重
This is serious.
我说我们应该回到老巢
I say we had to our lair
拿起我们的反电子圆宫装备
pick up our anti-Technodrome gear
好好利用它
and go put it to good use.
但首先
But first
我们得去救艾普尔
we've got to save April.
我们每天至少拯救一次艾普尔
We save April at least once a day.
没错
Yeah!
基本上每天准时开救
You can set your watch to it.
那是一个变种...香蕉?
Was that a mutant... banana?
这个维度真是乱七八糟的
This dimension is seriously messed up.
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
天哪 你们几个不在的时候
Boy, when you guys are out of town
针对我的生命威胁真是堆积如山
the threats on my life sure do pile up.
现在有八个你们了
There are eight of you now!
我的乖乖
Holy scoop!
等等 你是艾普尔
Wait. You're April?
呃 这套黄色连体服是什么情况
Um, what's with the yellow jumpsuit?
这个维度的你在洗车行工作吗
Do you work at a carwash in this dimension?
我是个记者 艾普尔·奥尼尔
I'm a reporter, April O'Neil.
而你们是我拿皮博迪奖的门票
And you are my ticket to a Peabody.
抱歉 艾普尔
Sorry, April.
没时间搞独家报道了
No time for an exclusive.
我们得把这些家伙带到老巢去
We've got to get these guys to the lair.
跟我来
Follow me!
我的眼睛
My eye!
欢迎回家 我的乌龟们
Welcome home, my Turtles.
还有我的乌龟们?
And my Turtles?
我会把装备收拾好的
I'll get that gear together
我们很快就能上路了
and we'll be on our way in no time.
搓头大法
Noogie!
嘿 住手
Hey, cut it out!
请利用这一刻滋养你们的身体和灵魂
Please, take this moment to nourish your body and soul
以准备迎接摆在你们面前的挑战
as you prepare for the challenge that lies ahead of you.
谢谢 师父
Thank you... Master.
我和我的兄弟们发现你的维度有点...
My brothers and I have found your dimension to be...
嗯...让人摸不着头脑 但来到这里
well... disorienting, but being here
见到了你 感觉就对了
seeing you feels right.
我也一样 李奥纳多
To me, also, Leonardo.
这里永远欢迎你们四位
You four are welcome here always.
我们的斯普林特老师也是这么说的
That's kind of what our Master Splinter said
对他们四个
to us about them.
我知道
I know.
我也很担心他
I'm worried about him, too.
这是什么
What is this?
我要的是乌龟
I asked for the Turtles,
你却带回了他们的...
and you bring me back their...
老鼠
rat?!
他们的巢穴坍塌的时候
We became separated
我们被分隔开了
when their lair collapsed around us.
不过 请放心 主人
But rest assured, Master
只要你手上有这只老鼠
as long as you have the rodent...
乌龟们会自己找上门的
the Turtles will come to you.
父亲 做这些是为了什么
Father, what is this all about?
乌龟们
The Turtles.
为了让我的计划继续下去
For my plans to proceed
必须得到它们
I must have them.
你做得很好 韩
You have done well, Hun.
现在
Now...
让我们变得更容易被找到
let us make ourselves easier to find.
是时候 崛起了!
The time has come to rise!
他们还是没接电话
They're still not answering.
我跟你说 凯西 有事情不对劲
I'm telling you, Casey, something's wrong.
我肯定他们没事的 艾普尔
I'm sure they're fine, April.
我是说 看看周围
I mean, take a look around.
多美丽的夜晚
It's a beautiful night.
一切安然无恙
Everything's peachy.
我刚刚说的什么
What I said about peachy?
当我没说
Never mind.
好了 大伙儿
Okay, guys,
这些就是我们需要的东西
here's everything we'll need
有这些就能拿下电子圆宫了
to take down the Technodrome.
爆炸飞镖
Exploding throwing stars
反电子圆宫轮滑鞋
anti-Technodrome roller skates
SPF-1000 防晒霜
SPF-1000 sun block.
我订了披萨
And I got the pizzas.
我们可以出发了
We're good to go.
你们在开玩笑吧
You're joking, right?
我们大老远来到这个怪世界 就是为了这些垃圾
We came all the way to Wacky World for this junk?
不! 不! 不! 不! 不!
No! No! No! No! No! No! no!
现在让我们打开传送门回到你们的世界
Now let's open up a portal back into your world
去踢施莱德的屁股吧
and go kick Shredder's butt!
什么玩意儿
What the shell?!
那是电子圆宫吗
Is that the Technodrome?
伙计们 我觉得这次
Dudes, I don't think
爆炸飞镖可能砍不动它了
exploding throwing stars are gonna cut it this time!
不
No!
看来电子圆宫已经被改造过了
Look like the Technodrome got itself a makover...
用了乌特罗姆科技
of the Utrom kind.
那么 是时候让咱们最牛的两部座驾出场了
Then maybe it's time we bust out two of our baddest rides!
什么 那些修理间的小破车?
What? Your clown cars in the shop?
动起来 动起来 速度加快
Move it! Move it! Double time!
他们真的以为靠军队就能阻止电子圆宫?
Did they really believe their military could stop this Technodrome?
一群蠢货
Fools!
他真的很厉害
He's quite good there.
嘘! 我不想错过好戏
Shh! I don't want to miss anything.
我的进攻才刚刚开始
My onslaught has only just begun!
咕嘎啦!
Goongala!
这些到底是什么玩意儿
What the heck are this things?
不管是什么 我们都要阻止他们 凯西
Whatever they are, we got to stop them, casey.
凯西 我被击中了
casey, i been hit!
艾普尔 快弹射
April! Eject!
接得好
Nice catch.
如果想赢得这场比赛 我们需要一个奇迹
But we need a miracle if we gonna win this game.
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
完了
Crud!
偏偏被凯西看见咱们坐在这辆愚蠢的面包车里
Why did Casey have to see us in this stupid van?
准确的说法是 愚蠢的派对战车
The technical term is stupid party wagon.
咱们还算好的 拉斐尔
Could be worse, Raph.
这是史上所有蹩脚车里最蹩脚的一辆了
This is the lamest vehicle in the history of lame vehicles.
这玩意儿就不能开快点吗
Can't this thing go any faster?!
当然能
Sure.
但是 我不建议这么做
But, I wouldn't recommend it.
为什么
Why not?
展示给你看比较容易
Easier just to show you, dude.
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga!
说真的 这车也没那么差
You know, this wagon isn't half bad.
也没好到哪里去
It ain't half good either.
我们只是在给这些丑八怪挠痒痒
We're just tickling these uglies.
我们需要...
We need...
空中支援
air support!
俗话说 只要活着走出来就是成功的降落
Well, they say any landing you can walk away...
搓头大法回归
Return of the noogies.
住手
Cut it out!
来吧
Come on.
让我们彻底结束这一切
Let's end this once and for all.
很好 到我这里来 乌龟们
Yes, come to me, Turtles.
你还在等什么
What the devil are you waiting for?
他们就在你的靶子上
They're right in your crosshairs.
赶紧消灭他们
Destroy them already.
把这些小丑绑起来
Restrain these buffoons.
对不起了 老大
Sorry, boss.
放开我
Unhand me!
我的跨维度律师会起诉你的
You'll hear from my transdimensional attorney!
嘿 他们铺了迎宾毯
Hey, they rolled out the welcome mat.
那我怎么一点都不觉得受欢迎呢
Then how come I ain't feeling welcome?
你们不明白
You don't understand.
乌特罗姆施莱德和你们的施莱德不一样
The Utrom Shredder isn't like your Shredder.
他心狠手辣
He's vicious.
杀人如麻
Lethal.
武力高强
Competent!
我们进去了 不一定能活着出来
We go in, no saying if we come out.
我们一起上
Let's do this.
今天 我们不仅仅是盟友
Today, we're more than allies.
我们是兄弟
We're brothers.
出发 绿色战车!
Go, Green Machine!
忍者时间到!
It's Ninja time!
神龟力量!
Turtle power!
烦人力量
Annoying power.
嘿
Hey!
动起来 龟小子
Move it, half-shell.
别推了
Quit shoving!
乌龟们
Turtles.
感谢你们接受我谦逊的邀请
Thank you for accepting my humble invitation.
你不是说他很强悍吗
Thought you said he was tough.
孩子们 这是个陷阱
My sons, it is a trap.
如果多元宇宙中有什么是常量
If there is one constant in the multiverse
那就是这帮乌龟的可预测性
it is the predictability of you Turtles.
只要威胁到你们在乎的东西
Threaten something you hold dear
你们就容易失去判断力
and you will ignore your better instincts.
你们应该躲得远远的
You should have stayed away.
现在 我们可以开始了吗
Now, shall we begin?
如果你要杀我们
If you plan on doing us in,
一定有更简单的方法
there's got to be an easier way.
你们会消亡的 但不是现在
You shall perish, but not yet.
你知道吗
You see,
我和你们一样 最近才认识到
like you, I recently learned that
我们的世界 只是多维度的宇宙中的一个维度
ours is but a single dimension in a multiverse of dimensions.
兴趣驱使我进入传送门调查了所有维度
Intrigued, I used this very portal to survey them all.
我发现了一个令人震惊的可怕事实
Which is when I made a startling, horrible discovery.
你们不只有八个
There are not simply eight of you
而是无数个
but scores of you.
看哪
Behold!
被诅咒的忍者龟的多元宇宙
A multiverse of accursed Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
太酷了
Awesome!
只摧毁你们八个一点用都没有
Destroying the eight of you would accomplish nothing.
只要多元宇宙中的还存在忍者龟
So long as Ninja Turtles exist somewhere in the multiverse,
他们就会干扰施莱德的计划
they will interfere in the plans of the Shredder.
我们之间的战斗永远不会结束
Our epic battle is never going to end
除非我永远消灭忍者龟
unless I put an end to Turtles forever!
即使像你这般痴迷权力的魔头
Even a creature as power-mad as you
也不应相信自己能够颠覆多元宇宙
cannot believe he has the ability to subvert the entire multiverse.
让我们来测试一下 害虫
Let us put that to a test, vermin.
就像树枝依附于树干一样
It seems that like branches hanging off a single tree
所有的维度都产生自一个共同的起源
each of these dimensions sprang from a common source.
摧毁源头 就会引发连锁反应
Destroy the source and you would set off a chain reaction
摧毁所有地方的忍者龟
that would destroy Ninja Turtles everywhere
直到永恒
forevermore.
所以 你们会被扫描 被分解
And so, you are being scanned, broken down,
全是为了查找你们的起源DNA
for the sole purpose of discovering your source DNA.
来自两个世界的两支乌龟队伍
Two Turtle teams from two Turtle worlds.
在很多方面各有不同
Different in so many ways
但是追根究底 有着相似的基因
but deep down, there are similarities.
这些相似点会为我们指明道路
And those similarities shall point the path
找到起源维度
to the source dimension
起源神龟
Turtle Prime.
可惜的是 你们没法活着
I only regret you will not survive
亲眼见证自己的末日...
to witness the end of your...
父亲
Father.
我们收到了令人担忧且不稳定的能量读数
We are receiving alarming and unstable energy readings.
这是怎么回事
What is going on...?
不
No!
我们那边从来不会发生这种事
Things like this never happened back home.
起源神龟已定位
Turtle Prime located.
成功了
It works.
维度传送门
The transdimensional portal
正在接收坐标
is receiving the coordinates now.
永别了 乌龟们
Farewell, Turtles!
不
No!
他们的死亡只是个开始
Their demise is only the beginning.
那个大型装甲保龄球刚刚爆炸了
That giant armored bowling ball just imploded.
一定是它在控制机器人
He must have been controlling the robots.
没有了船 就没有能量了
No ship, no power.
凯西 我们赢了
Casey, we've won.
赢了?
Won?
艾普尔
April,
没有船 乌龟们也没了
No ship, no Turtles.
他们走进了那玩意儿里
They went into that thing and
现在他们...他们...
now they're... they're...
伙计们 你们还活着
Guys, you're alive!
老兄 刚刚发生了什么
Dudes, like, what just happened?
是啊 我们现在不是应该...不存在了吗
Yeah. Shouldn't we be, like, nonexistent right about now?
麦琪
Mikey!
还有...麦琪?
And... Mikey?
是我撞昏头了 还是看到了重影?
I bump my head, or am I really seeing double?
凯西 艾普尔
Casey, April,
见见我们另一个维度的分身
meet our dimensional duplicates.
没时间给你们见面打招呼了
We ain't got time for no meet-and-greet.
拉斐尔是对的
Raph's right.
施莱德回来了 而且他已经出发
The Shredder's back, and he's on his way
去摧毁所有忍者神龟的生命源头
to destroy the source of all Ninja Turtle life.
什么! 你再说一遍?
What?! Come again?
如果我们不阻止他
If we don't stop it,
这可能意味着所有忍者神龟的终结
it could spell the end of Ninja Turtles everywhere
永远消失
forever.
所以 我还是不明白
So, I still don't get it.
哪个施莱德回来了? 在做什么? 对谁做?
Which Shredder is back, doing what? To who?
我知道的是 如果不是因为你们的施莱德
All I know is we wouldn't be in this mess
我们就不会陷入这种境地
if it wasn't for your stupid shredder.
我们的施莱德?
Our Shredder?
明明是你们的施莱德先引起的混乱
Your Shredder started this whole stupid mess
用他那个愚蠢的电子圆宫
with a stupid technotrome in the stupid first place.
是的 但你们的施莱德简直就是个邪恶的疯子
Yes, but your shredder is like totally psycho evil.
我们的属于无糖饮料
Ours is just decaf.
是的 他不会让你晚上睡不着的
Yes, he won't keep you up at night.
说得好 老兄 你听懂了吗
Good one, dude. Get it?
这些重影看来是脑子没带齐 是吧?
Doubles ain't exactly laying with a full deck, are they?
而且他们真的很烦人
And they are really annoying.
明白了 现在跟上状况了
Got'ya. Up to speed now.
我想知道的是
What I want to know is,
我们是怎么从施莱德的离心扫描程序中活下来的
how did we survive the Shredder's centrifugal scanning process?
按理说 我们早应该被分解到不存在了
We should have been broken down into nonexistence.
有些事情没有按照他的计划进行
Something didn't go according to his plan.
那他就不会料到我们会去追他了
Then he won't be expecting us to go after him.
我们需要前往起源维度
We need to head to the source dimension
寻找施莱德所说的起源神龟
to what the Shredder called Turtle Prime.
但是 李奥 你也看过施莱德的幻灯片了
But, Leo, you saw Shredder's slide show.
神龟宇宙简直超级无敌大
The turtleverse is like, ginormous.
我们怎么知道起源龟在哪个维度
We have no way of knowing which dimension Turtle Prime is.
我们只能猜了
We'd just be guessing.
或者 我们可以跟随你们的施莱德的脚步
Or we could track your Shredder's exact movements instead.
当电子圆宫穿过维度屏障时
When the Technodrome phases through transdimensional barriers,
它会留下粒子排放的痕迹
it leaves a trail of particle emissions
这样 只需要有合适的设备
that, with the right equipment
我们就可以校准传送杆去追踪了
we can recalibrate the portal stick to track.
怎么回事 拉斐尔
What the shell, Raph?!
没路了 兄弟们
End of the road, bros.
字面意思
Literally!
好像整个世界正在被抹去
It's like the whole world's being erased.
是施莱德 肯定是
It's the Shredder-- has to be.
他已经找到了起源神龟
He's reached Turtle Prime.
那我们最好快点校准你的跟踪装置
Then we'd better recalibrate your tracking device.
你们不是说需要一些设备吗
You said you needed some equipment?
我们所有的装备都和家一起被摧毁了
All our gear was destroyed along with our lair.
但是我觉得有一个地方
But I think I know a place
可能有我们需要的技术
that just might have the tech we need.
赶快
Come on!
紫龙帮总部
Purple Dragon headquarters.
好主意啊 巫师先生
Nice call, Mr. Wizard.
我就猜到紫龙帮还留着一些
I figured the Purple Dragons would still have the goods
那次抢劫弄来的货
from that robbery they pulled.
是啊 没有韩 紫龙帮就群龙无首了
Yeah, without Hun, the Dragons ain't too swift.
能快点吗 兄弟们
Step on it, home slices.
这地方有点吓人
This place bugs me out.
没错
Yes.
变异
Mutation
才是一场真正的恐怖秀
it's a real horror show.
我不知道你是怎么逃过施莱德的
I don't know how you escaped the Shredder
我也不在乎
and I don't care.
现在 你们都是我的了
You're all mine now.
韩
Hun.
那是韩?
Hon?
是韩
Hun.
你知道我最讨厌的东西是什么吗
Do you know the thing I hate most in all the world?
乌龟
Turtles!
后空翻
Alley-oop.
现在 我每次看镜子
Now I look in the mirror
就会看到你们
all I see is you.
这让我更恨你们
And I hate you even more!
韩 你不明白
Hun, you don't understand
施莱德 他...
The Shredder, he...
忘了施莱德吧
Forget the Shredder.
你们要为对我做的事付出代价
You're going to pay for what you've done to me.
有些人就是接受不了变化
Some people just can't handle change.
你为什么一直那样做
Why do you keep doing that?
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
那里根本没有人
There's no one there.
你个白痴 很快就会哪里都没有人了
You idiot. There ain't gonna be anybody anywhere soon.
看
Look!
头儿 这是怎么回事
Boss, what's happening to...?
整个世界都要没了 老兄
The whole world is going bye-bye, dude.
很快就连你也没了
Pretty soon you'll be going, too.
不
No.
我们需要你的装备来追踪他 韩
We need your gear to track him, Hun.
为了阻止他
To stop him.
快点 拿着
Hurry, take it!
阻止他
Stop him!
阻止施莱德毁灭...
Stop the Shredder before he...
你们听到他说的了
You heard the man.
我们去阻止施莱德吧
Let's go stop the Shredder.
快点 我们需要回到最开始的地方
Hurry! We need to get back to where we started.
电子圆宫从我们维度消失的地点
The exact spot the Technodrome left our dimension.
那个冒烟的大坑?
Big smoking crater?
不难找
Hard to miss.
除非它在我们到达之前消失
Unless it disappears before we get there.
不! 凯西
No! Casey!
它发生在我身上了
It's happening to me!
艾普尔
April!
伙计们 艾普尔
Guys, April...
她...她消失了
She... she's disappeared!
不
No!
凯西
Casey!
拉斐尔
Raph,
我们不能停下来
we can't stop.
我们得继续前进
We have to keep moving.
就在这里
Right here.
只需要修改一下维度相变器的路线
Just have to reroute the dimensional phase converter.
兔子爬出洞 绕过树
The rabbit goes up the hole, around the tree
然后回到洞里去
and back down the hole.
快点 伙计们
Step on it, dudes.
我们面对的可是彻底的毁灭
We're facing total, complete wipeout here.
提高粒子信号增益
Boost the particle signal gain.
我们太酷了 不能死!
We're too cool to go!
然后启动
And power up.
但是 但是...
But, but...
但是? 但是?
But? But?
但是?
But?
不起作用
It's not working.
粒子踪迹终止在这里
The particle emissions end here.
所以一定就是这里了
So this must be the place.
起源神龟
Turtle Prime.
我想回家
I want to go home.
不像是什么友好邻居的小区 是吗
Ain't exactly Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, is it?
这是个什么世界
Like what kind of world is this?
冷酷 粗犷
Grim, gritty
是我喜欢的地方
my kind of place.
料到了
Figures.
啊 我想在这里退休
I'm thinking of retiring here.
我们都得在这里永久退休了
We'll all be retiring here permanently
如果不快点找到施莱德并阻止他
if we don't find the Shredder and stop him.
李奥 我想有人找到我们了
Leo, I think someone just found us.
起源维度的...
Source dimension--
起源神龟
source turtles!
这是什么 八个冒牌货
What is this, eight wannabes?
在我们的地盘上
On our turf?
想抢走我们的风头?
Trying to steal our act?
好
Yeah.
我下来的路上击倒了两个
I strike two on my way down.
多纳泰罗用他的长棍拿下了第三个
Donatello takes out a third with his staff.
胖乎乎那几个开始慌了
Already the pudgy ones are starting to panic.
拉斐尔乐在其中
Raph loves this stuff.
他并不孤单
He's not alone.
他为什么要配旁白 他疯了吗
Why is he narrating? Is he crazy?
铁杆疯子
Hardcore crazy.
我喜欢这些家伙
I love these guys.
停下
Stop!
我们是想救你们...
We're trying to save you from the...
阻止施莱德
from the Shredder!
施莱德
The Shredder?
你们对施莱德了解多少
What do you know of the Shredder?
我们发誓要消灭施莱德 为耀西师傅报仇
We sworn to terminate the Shredder to avenge Master Yoshi.
毫不留情地消灭
Terminate with extreme prejudice.
你们要担心的不是你们的施莱德
It's not your Shredder you need to worry about.
当然 暂时不是
Well, not right now.
事情有点复杂
It's complicated.
是我们的施莱德 他来这里要摧毁你的世界
It's our Shredder; he's come here to tear down your world.
他是个一级坏蛋
And he's a grade-A meanie.
呃 说来话长
It's a long story.
但这一切都始于我们这些兄弟...
But it's all started when our brothers here
来自另一个维度...
from another dimension...
...所有忍者乌龟的生命
...to all ninjas turtle life.
如果我们的施莱德毁掉起源神龟
So if our shredder destroy turtle prime
最终会导致毁灭所有的生命
he'll end up wiping out all life everywhere.
所以你们就是来自另一个世界的我们
So you're supposed to be us from other worlds?
我看不出来
I don't see it.
这些五颜六色的发带是怎么回事
What's with the multi-colored headbands?
叛徒
Sellouts.
[双关: 用来圈钱的]
呃 看看这些家伙身上的带首字母的皮带扣
Well, check out the initialized belt buckles on these yahoos.
嘿
Hey!
这才叫逊呢
How lame can a turtle get?
我说的对吗
Am I right?
嘿
Hey!
天啊 暴躁的家伙
Geez, what a hard case.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
好了 我们去阻止你们的施莱德
All right, let's go stop your Shredder.
你说他用了什么电子圆宫?
You say he's using a Technodrome?
是的 但别担心
Yep. But don't worry,
我们制造了一个复杂的设备
we've created a sophisticated device
它能追踪电子圆宫
that will be able to track the Technodrome
无论它在哪里...是那个吗?
no matter where... Is that it?
是的 就是它了
Yep, that would be it.
它整晚都在这么做
It's been doing that all night.
现在我们去做点什么吧
Now let's go do something about it.
你们这些叛徒 蠢货
You traitors. You nincompoops.
笨蛋 呆子 二货们
ding-dongs, Chucklebutts, dip-skulls.
我们说过抱歉了 老大
We said we were sorry, boss.
拜托 别太在意好吗
Come on. No hard feelings?
我们的新主人觉得我们挺有趣 仅此而已
Our new master find us amusing, is all.
这样的话 希望他会觉得你们和我们一样有用
If then, may he also find you as useful as we always have.
看吧 宇宙毁灭的荣光
Behold the glorious destruction of a universe.
随之而来的是忍者神龟的终结
And with it, the end of the Ninja Turtles.
施莱德
Shredder
我们来了
we are here!
施莱德 面对我们
Shredder, face us.
乌龟的原型
The prototypical Turtles.
终于来了
At last.
现在 只要轻轻一按开关
Now with the flick of a switch
一切都结束了
it ends.
施莱德
Shredder!
你在害怕我们吗
Do you fear us?
我就在这里
I am here.
来面对你们的...
Come and face your...
施莱德
Shredder!
你们叫着我的名字
You speak my name
但是并不认识我
but you do not know me.
我是迟瑞尔 小禄崎
I am Ch'rell, Oroku Sake
阿库拉公爵 唯一正宗施莱德
Duke Accureds -- the one true Shredder.
我是世界的毁灭者
I am a destroyer of worlds
我不怕任何人
and I fear no one!
我就说他会上钩的
Told you he'd take the bait.
如果多重宇宙中有一个常量
If there's one constant in the mulitverse
那就是施莱德的狂妄自大
it's the Shredder's big, fat ego.
还活着
Still alive?
怎么可能
How can this be?
除非
Unless...
卡拉...你
Karai... you!
是的 父亲
Yes, Father.
我用了物质传送器
I used the matter transporter
从你的扫描仪里救出乌龟
to rescue the Turtles from your scanner.
这还不是全部
And that's not all.
今天 我的孩子们不再孤军奋战
Today my sons do not fight alone.
这下我们肯定要被骂死了
we is so gonna get yelled at for this.
你对乌龟们的盲目仇恨
Your unreasoning hatred of the Turtles
已经蒙蔽了你的双眼 父亲
has blinded you to the truth, Father.
你的行为可能会毁了我们所有人
Your actions could destroy us all.
卡拉是对的
Karai's right.
无论你在做什么
Whatever you're doing
你已经毁灭了我们的整个世界
you've already wiped out our entire world.
蠢货
Fool.
我根本不在乎那些我丢下宇宙
I care nothing for the universe I left behind.
我绝不会停下来 直到...
I will not stop until...
少废话 多行动
Less talk, more action.
让我们彻底了结这一切
Let us finish this once and for all.
我来到这个维度
I came to this dimension
是为了消灭乌龟
to destroy Turtles.
杀的越多
The more...
我越高兴
...the merrier!
现在来吧
Now come
过来面对你们的毁灭吧
come and face your doom!
一切都太简单了
All too easy.
我的新身体给了我无限的力量
My new body gives me unlimited power.
别忘了 你不是唯一一个拥有分子生物放大战衣的人
You're not the only one with a molecular amplification bio suit, you know.
然而我的战衣才真正管用
But mine actually works.
恶
Ew!
今天是你们的末日 乌龟们
Today is the end of days for you, Turtles.
还有站在你们那边的所有人
You and all who stand with you.
当心
Look out!
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
没用的 他太强大了
It's no use. He's just too strong.
是真的
Tell me about it.
连垃圾桶都没有效果
Even trash cans have no effect.
兄弟啊
Brother.
当心
Look out!
好的 好的 没事啦
Yeah, okay, it's okay.
你们可以放手了 放手
You can let go now. Let go.
别逼我揍你们
Don't make me hurt you.
嘿 有人看见那些经典款神龟了吗
Hey, anybody seen the Turtle's classics?
我们自由了
We're free.
看来我们找到了他的弱点
Looks like we just found something he's vulnerable to.
好啊
Yeah
神龟之力
Turtles.
电子圆宫
The Technodrome.
谁能想到
Go figure.
把他引到光束上
Get him into that beam!
我们得救主人
We got to save the master.
你们的机会用完了
You had your chance.
现在该我了
Now I have mine.
没有这些乌龟 你们就不会存在
Without these Turtles, you cannot exist.
看吧
Behold!
直到现在 最后一刻 你们才真正明白
Only now, in the end, do you truly understand.
我这是怎么了
What is happening to me?
父亲 请停手吧
Father, stop. Please.
你不明白吗
Can you not see?
无论你做了什么来摧毁他们
Whatever it is you have done to destroy them?
这也会摧毁我们所有人
You do it to all of us as well.
我们命运是相连的
Our fates are linked to theirs.
不 这不可能
No, this cannot be.
父亲 我不想再次失去你
Father, i don't want to lose you again.
摧毁它们 你就会毁灭你自己
Destroy them And you will destroy yourself.
我求你了
I beg you.
停手吧
Stop.
不 我是施莱德 忍者神龟的屠杀者
No. I am the shredder. Slayer of Ninja Turtles.
如果摧毁它们意味着一切的终结
If destroying them means the end of everything
那就毁灭吧
then so be it.
爆炸飞镖
Exploding throwing stars.
我就说会派上用场的
Told you they'd come in handy.
蠢货
Fools,
你们可怜的小玩具根本不足以阻止我
your pathetic little toys are not enough to stop me.
我会...
I will...
很简单的修理
That was an easy fix.
主人会很高兴的
The master will be pleased.
不! 不! 不!
No! No! No!
我绝不会...
I will not...
我是...
I am...
不
No!!
施莱德已经被粉碎了
The Shredder has been shredded.
在我看来 起源龟们康复得相当不错
I'd say Turtle Prime is healing up rather nicely.
看来维度的破坏只是暂时的
It seems the dimensional damage was only temporary
只要起源龟们还活着
so long as Turtle Prime survived.
希望这意味着...
Which hopefully means...
我们的世界也在痊愈吗
Our world is healing, too?
我知道一个有趣的方法来找出答案
I know a fun way to find out.
凯西! 艾普尔!
- Casey! - April!
好了 好了 表演结束了 你们这些笨蛋
All right, all right, show's over, you goofballs.
-我爱你 凯西 -我爱你 艾普尔
- I wuv you, Casey. - I wuv you, April.
他们有什么毛病
What is wrong with them?
李奥纳多
Leonardo
说真的 为了你们自己好
seriously, for your own good
你们几个兄弟别再搞维度跨跃这种事了
you bros should lay off the dimension hopping business.
太危险了
It's dangerous.
兄弟
Bros?
他叫我们兄弟
We're bros.
这才叫真正的忍者消失术
Now that's what I call a Ninja vanish.
你们的施莱德怎么办
What about your Shredder?
你觉得他这次真的是一去不复返了吗
Think he's really gone for good this time?
施莱德很少会消失很久
The Shredder is seldom gone for long.
他会回来的
He shall return.
哼 等我回来的时候
Well, when I get back
我要用克朗发明的傻笑光线轰炸你们
I'm going to zap you all with the giggle ray Krang invented.
请放心 笑到最后的一定是我们
And rest assured, it will be us who get the last laugh.
抱歉
Excuse me.
嘿 带我们一起去吧
Hey, take us with ya.
我们已经道过歉了
We said we was sorry.
照顾好自己 我的兄弟们
Take care of yourselves, my brothers.
多元宇宙再见 兄弟们
See you around the multiverse, bros.
忍者时间到
It's Ninja time!
神龟力量
Turtle power!
我会想念这些小胖墩的
I'm gonna miss those pudge-balls.
才怪
Not.
我会想念那些冒牌货的
I'm gonna miss those wannabes.
是的 我还挺喜欢皮带扣上的首字母的
Yeah, I kind of dug the initials on the belt buckles.
知道你会的
You would.
我想去吃片匹萨
I could go for a slice, though.
布利克街有个好地方
There's that place on Bleeker.
我们是忍者神龟
We are the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
我们迅猛出击
We strike hard
然后消失在夜色中
and fade away into the night.
我认为第一期进展得相当顺利
I think this first issue is coming along rather well,
不是吗 凯文
don't you, Kev?
是啊 当然 皮特
Yeah, sure do, Pete.
嘿 我们吃完午饭再说这个吧
Hey, let's get back to this after lunch?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
匹萨?
Pizza?
好的 匹萨
Yeah, pizza.
我真希望这玩意儿能卖出去
I sure hope this thing sells.
是啊 我也是这么想的
Yeah, I was thinking the same thing.
永远的忍者神龟
♪十五年的训练 我们心无旁骛♪
♪ 15 years we trained without distraction ♪
♪现在是时候大展拳脚了♪
♪ Now it's time for Ninja kick-butt action ♪
♪想要寻找归属♪
♪ Trying to find the place ♪
♪却不知道往哪里去♪
♪ But we don't know where we're headed ♪
♪唯一确定的是 别被施莱德撕碎♪
♪ All we know for sure, don't wanna get shredded ♪
♪青少年变种忍者神龟♪
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles ♪
♪我们悄无声息 迅如疾风♪
♪ You'll never see us comin', never know what hit you ♪
♪我们的忍者隐身术 来去无踪♪
♪ We practice Teenage Mutant Turtle stealth Ninjitsu ♪
♪潜行于阴影之中 我们独立行动♪
♪ Keepin' to the shadows where we walk alone ♪
♪出击的时候 我们大喊卡哇邦嘎♪
♪ When it's time to strike, it's Cowabunga ♪
♪青少年变种忍者神龟♪
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles ♪
忍者时间到
It's Ninja time!
♪青少年变种忍者神龟♪
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles ♪
♪神龟报数♪
♪ Turtles count it off ♪
♪一 李奥纳多总是善于克制♪
♪ One, Leonardo's always in control ♪
♪二 这个聪明的家伙是米开朗基罗♪
♪ Two, the wise guy is Michelangelo ♪
♪三 多纳泰罗是团队的大脑♪
♪ Three, Donatello, he's the brains of the bunch ♪
♪四 拉斐尔会给你一记重拳♪
♪ Four, count on Raphael to throw the first punch ♪
♪我喜欢做一只...♪
♪ I love being, I love being ♪
♪我喜欢做一只忍者神龟♪
♪ I love being a Turtle ♪
♪青少年变种忍者神龟♪
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles. ♪
我喜欢做一只忍者神龟
I love being a Turtle!